Preben Rønningen

Software Developer

Summary

Highly motivated game programmer who is focused on building a career in the games industry. Experienced in Engine and Graphics programming with C++. Years of both university and professional experience using programming languages such as C++ and C#.

Good knowledge of object-oriented development.

Knowledge of common algorithms, data structures, game programming patterns and the ability to apply them to problems while keeping memory and performance constraints in mind.

Good debugging, troubleshooting and optimization skills.

Experience

Gameplay Programmer - Neopica, Belgium

- Feature integration.
- Multiplayer and single player development.
- UI Implementation
- Unreal Engine 5. C++

October 2022 - Present

Programmer – Frozenbyte, Finland

- · Finishing and fixing half made features, and bug fixing.
- Worked on features and integration.
- Cross-Platform development environment
- In-house Engine / Editor, C++

February 2022 - May 2022

Education

BSc in Game Development at HOWEST University of Applied Sciences, Digital Arts and Entertainment, Kortrijk, Belgium.

September 2018 - June 2022

Game Graphics Production at HOWEST University of Applied Sciences, Digital Arts and Entertainment, Kortrijk, Belgium.

September 2016 – June 2018

Game and Entertainment Technology at Nord University, Nord-Trøndelag, Norway.

August 2015 - June 2016

Skills

Programming

Languages: C++ / C# / Python (basic knowledge)

API: DirectX11 / OpenGL / SDL / SFML / ImGui

Commercial Game Engines: Unreal Engine 4 & 5 / Unity3D

Software: Visual Studio / Nvidia NSight / SHADERed / Perforce / Git /

(Tortoise) SVN

Additional knowledge

3DS Max / Maya / Photoshop / Substance Painter & Designer / Quixel

Contact

Email: Preben.ronningen@mail.com

Links

PrebenRonningen.github.io

in In/PrebenRonningen

() /PrebenRonningen

Languages

Norwegian - Native English – Professional (C2)

Soft Skills

Problem Solving

Teamwork

Critical-Thinking

Self-Management

Taking initiative

Creative